Oluwaferanmi (Olu) Owolabi

oluwaferanmiowolabi@gmail.com, mobile 469.600.2594, web: oluowolabi.github.io 2007 Tasmanian Tiger Trc, Austin, Tx 78728.

Goal: Seeking internship opportunity of being part of an innovative software company with entrepreneurial and global aims.

Skills and Projects

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Jekyll.

Strong experience with Object-oriented coding in C++ and Java.

Created projects using APIs of popular android apps and working with Facebook technicians to build apps using android studio.

Use of Arduino board to build prototypes for different household equipment such as thermometer, reactive LED-lights, lawn sprinkler and toys for kids.

Raspberry Pi usage to develop tutorials for Kali-Linux, Android Things and Docker.

Use of GitHub to manage projects on local and remote machine.

Proficient with Git, Mercurial, Subversion, Microsoft Office, Scripting, PowerShell, SQL, Security+. OS: Linux, Macintosh OS, Windows, Android OS,

English and Yoruba (fluent), French (familiar).

VirtualBox for simulation of multiple operating systems on a Virtual Machine (VM).

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, University of North Texas, *Denton, Texas*, May 2020 Associate of Science, Computer Science, Austin Community College, *Austin, Texas*, July 2018, GPA 3.5.

Undergraduate study, Richland College, Dallas, Texas, July 2017, 37 credit hours, GPA 3.6. Culminating project: design of code used to approve credit card applications.

Diploma, Gray's International College, Ede, Osun State, Nigeria, July 2012.

Work Experience

•		
Crew Member, Subway Restaurant, Dallas, Texas	8/2016-5/2017	
Factory Manager, Next Table Water, Osun, Nigeria	6/2013-3/2016	
Managed 20 customer accounts from order to fulfilment to payment.		
Generated reports and metrics to assist in operations decisions.		

Managed departments and personnel within the organization.

Part-time sales associate, Next Table Water, Osun, Nigeria 6/2013–3/2016 Learned entrepreneurial skills necessary for small businesses.

Leadership Activities

on schedule

•	Students with Vision, career-advancement for varied majors	7/2016-5/2019
•	Africa Student Association, social support network	7/2016-5/2017
•	Dallas Habitat for Humanity, affordable housing project	5/2016-8/2016
	 Co-led efforts to provide affordable housing. Oversaw all 	
	engagement, organized members and ensure project was	

Jesus House-Dallas, foster children program
 7/2016-5/2017